<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Marblerun - The service mesh for confidential computing on Marblerun - The Service Mesh for Confidential Computing</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/</link><description>Recent content in Marblerun - The service mesh for confidential computing on Marblerun - The Service Mesh for Confidential Computing</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 15:33:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marblerun.sh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Attestation</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/features/attestation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 16:28:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/features/attestation/</guid><description>Attestation Hardware-rooted remote attestation is a key ingredient for distributed confidential apps. Without it, services couldn&amp;rsquo;t trust each other and clients couldn&amp;rsquo;t trust the app. Thus, Marblerun relies heavily on the Data Center Attestation Primitives (DCAP) of the latest SGX-enabled Intel Xeon processors. You can learn more about DCAP in the official Intel DCAP orientation. At the time of writing only Microsoft Azure had a public DCAP service deployed in their data-centers.</description></item><item><title>Deploying Marblerun</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/tasks/deploy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 16:28:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/tasks/deploy/</guid><description>Deploying Marblerun This article assumes that you have an existing Kubernetes cluster. Currently, there are several providers offering confidential nodes on CPUs with SGX support:
Azure Kubernetes Services confidential nodes on DCv2 VMs An AKS cluster can be created using the Azure CLI or the Azure portal Alibaba Cloud ECS Bare Metal Instances IBM Cloud Bare Metal Servers Equinix Bare Metal Servers Alternatively, you can deploy the steps with minikube Note that you need DCAP infrastructure in place for remote attestation to work.</description></item><item><title>Hello world</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/examples/helloworld/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 16:28:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/examples/helloworld/</guid><description>Hello world We have two basic examples of how to build confidential applications with Marblerun.
See helloworld for how to integrate Marblerun with your Golang application. See helloc++ for how integrate Marblerun with your C++ application.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 16:28:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/introduction/</guid><description>Introduction Marblerun is a framework for creating distributed confidential-computing apps.
Build your confidential microservices with EGo or another runtime, distribute them with Kubernetes on an SGX-enabled cluster, and let Marblerun take care of the rest. Deploy end-to-end secure and verifiable AI pipelines or crunch on sensitive big data in the cloud. Confidential computing at scale has never been easier.
Marblerun guarantees that the topology of your distributed app adheres to a Manifest specified in simple JSON.</description></item><item><title>Quickstart</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/getting-started/quickstart/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 16:28:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/getting-started/quickstart/</guid><description>Quickstart Set up a Kubernetes cluster and install kubectl. Probably the easiest way to get started is to run Kubernetes on your local machine using Minikube. Another easy way is to use Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS), which offers SGX-enabled nodes.
In this guide will show you how to deploy and verify the Confidential Emoji.voto application, an microservice that allows users to vote for their favorite emoji, and tracks votes received on a leaderboard.</description></item><item><title>Defining a Manifest</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/tasks/define-manifest/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 16:44:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/tasks/define-manifest/</guid><description>Defining a Manifest The Manifest is a simple JSON file that determines the key properties of your cluster: Packages, Marbles, Secrets, and RecoveryKeys. This article describes how to define these in your manifest.json.
Manifest:Packages The Packages section of the Manifest lists all the secure enclave software-packages that your application uses. A package is defined by the following properties.
UniqueID: this value will pin this package to one specific release build of an application.</description></item><item><title>Concepts</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/getting-started/concepts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 16:28:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/getting-started/concepts/</guid><description>Concepts This article describes the concepts of confidential computing and service meshes which are key to the Marblerun approach.
Confidential computing Confidential computing protects data in use by performing computation in hardware-based secure enclaves. The most prominent enclave to date is probably Intel SGX. Enclaves prevent unauthorized access or modification of applications and data while in use, thereby increasing the security assurances for organizations that manage sensitive and regulated data. For information about confidential computing, see the Confidential Computing Consortium white paper.</description></item><item><title>Emoji voting</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/examples/emojivoto/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 16:28:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/examples/emojivoto/</guid><description>Emoji voting The popular Linkerd service mesh uses the simple and fun scalable emojivoto app as the default demo. You can find our confidential variant on GitHub. Your emoji votes have never been safer!</description></item><item><title>Recovery</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/features/recovery/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 16:28:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/features/recovery/</guid><description>Recovery Persistent storage for confidential applications in the cloud requires a bit of attention. By design, SGX sealing keys are unique to a single CPU, which means using the default SGX sealing methods has some caveats. For example, sealing data while running on one host could mean the data can&amp;rsquo;t be unsealed when running on another host later on.
As described in our secrets management chapter, the Coordinator provides Marbles with virtual sealing keys making persistence straightforward for your applications.</description></item><item><title>Updating a Manifest</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/tasks/update-manifest/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 15:33:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/tasks/update-manifest/</guid><description>Updating a Manifest In order to ensure the confidentiality of a deployed application, Marblerun uses a Manifest to which defines the software packages and the infrastructure your deployment uses. To verify that your deployment has not been altered with, the Manifest is usually set in stone after it was set to ensure no one can alter with your cluster.
Yet, updates play an important role to ensure your software stays secure.</description></item><item><title>Coordinator</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/getting-started/coordinator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 16:30:52 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/getting-started/coordinator/</guid><description>Coordinator The Coordinator represents the control plane in Marblerun. It communicates with the data plane through gRPC and provides an HTTP-REST interface on the client-side. The Coordinator can be configured with several environment variables:
EDG_COORDINATOR_MESH_ADDR: The listener address for the gRPC server EDG_COORDINATOR_CLIENT_ADDR: The listener address for the HTTP server EDG_COORDINATOR_DNS_NAMES: The DNS names for the cluster&amp;rsquo;s root certificate EDG_COORDINATOR_SEAL_DIR: The file path for storing sealed data Client API The Coordinator clients can be devided into two major groups.</description></item><item><title>Secrets management</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/features/secrets-management/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 16:28:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/features/secrets-management/</guid><description>Secrets management The generation and the management of cryptographic keys and certificates for Marbles (i.e., containers running enclaves) are central duties of the Coordinator. Keys and certificates are passed to Marbles on startup via placeholders defined in the Manifest. You can learn more about this mechanism in our setting a manifest hands-on. Specifically, the Coordinator provides the following to Marbles.
Virtual sealing keys Shared symmetric keys TLS credentials Virtual sealing keys A key feature of Intel SGX is that it allows enclave software to derive so called &amp;ldquo;sealing keys&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Graphene-based examples</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/examples/graphene/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/examples/graphene/</guid><description>Graphene-based examples We provide two examples for Graphene-based Marbles:
A helloworld example to get you started. 🤓 An NGINX webserver for an example of converting an existing Graphene application to a Marble. 🚀</description></item><item><title>Marbles</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/getting-started/marbles/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 16:33:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/getting-started/marbles/</guid><description>Marbles Marbles represent the data plane in Marblerun and run your actual application code in secure enclaves within otherwise normal Docker containers. Marbles communicate with the Coordinator via gRPC over TLS. See the Add a Service section on how to build and configure a Marble.</description></item><item><title>Adding a service</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/tasks/add-service/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 16:28:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/tasks/add-service/</guid><description>Adding a service Adding a service to your application requires three steps, which are described in the following.
Step 1: Get your service ready for Marblerun To get your service ready for Marblerun, you need to rebuild it with one of the supported runtimes:
EGo Edgeless RT Graphene Make your service use the provided TLS credentials Quick refresher: Marblerun&amp;rsquo;s Coordinator issues TLS credentials for each verified Marble (i.e., a service running in a secure enclave) as is described in our secrets management chapter.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes integration</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/features/auto-injection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/features/auto-injection/</guid><description>Kubernetes integration Marblerun provides its data-plane configuration through Kubernetes resource definitions. For this, like regular service meshes, Marblerun uses Kubernetes' admission controllers.
Marblerun optionally injects tolerations and resources for its SGX device plugin. See the SGX Device Plugin section for more information.
You can enable auto-injection of the data-plane configuration for a namespace using the Marblerun CLI:
marblerun namespace add NAMESPACE [--no-sgx-injection] This will add the label marblerun/inject=enabled to the chosen namespace and allow the admission webhook to intercept the creation of deployments, pods, etc.</description></item><item><title>Supported Runtimes</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/features/runtimes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/features/runtimes/</guid><description>Supported Runtimes Marblerun strives to be runtime-agnostic. Currently supported runtimes are described below. More will follow in future.
EGo EGo is the preferred way for writing confidential Go applications from scratch as well as porting existing ones. Usage is very similar to conventional Go programming. Continue with our building a service with EGo hands-on to use it with Marblerun.
Edgeless RT With Edgeless RT you can create confidential C++ applications with a low TCB.</description></item><item><title>Planned features</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/features/planned-features/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 16:28:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/features/planned-features/</guid><description>Planned features Among others, the following features are planned for Marblerun.
Support for Occlum to facilitate the porting of existing software Splitting recovery key between a set of parties Fault-tolerant distribution of the Coordinator Transparent TLS for Marbles Constant-time crypto in the Coordinator Use online time sources for the verification of certificates and SGX collaterals</description></item><item><title>Building a service: EGo</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/tasks/build-service-ego/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/tasks/build-service-ego/</guid><description>Building a service: EGo To get your Go service ready for Marblerun, you possibly need to adapt its code slightly and you need to rebuild it. Details are given in the following. Note that we are working on making these unnecessary in the future.
Make your service use the provided TLS credentials If your service already uses TLS and gets the credentials from, e.g., a file, you just need to adapt the Manifest.</description></item><item><title>CLI</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/getting-started/cli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/getting-started/cli/</guid><description>Command Line Interface (CLI) We provide a command-line interface (CLI) for Marblerun. This CLI allows you to install Marblerun on your cluster and interacts with the control plane through the Client API for all administrative tasks in the service mesh.
To install the Marblerun CLI on your machine you can use our pre-built binaries.
For the current user wget -P ~/.local/bin/marblerun https://github.com/edgelesssys/marblerun/releases/latest/download/marblerun chmod +x ~/.local/bin/marblerun Global install (requires root) sudo wget -O /usr/local/bin/marblerun https://github.</description></item><item><title>Building a service: Graphene</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/tasks/build-service-graphene/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/tasks/build-service-graphene/</guid><description>Building a service: Graphene Running a Graphene app with Marblerun requires some changes to its manifest. These are explained in the following. See also the helloworld example.
Requirements First, get Graphene up and running. You can use either the Building or Cloud Deployment guide to build and initially setup Graphene.
Before running your application, make sure you got the prerequisites for ECDSA remote attestation installed on your system. You can collectively install them with the following command:</description></item><item><title>SGX device plugin</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/getting-started/sgx-device-plugin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/getting-started/sgx-device-plugin/</guid><description>SGX device plugin on Kubernetes Kubernetes manages hardware resources like Intel SGX through its device plugin framework. The SGX device plugin can either be deployed manually or as a DaemonSet in the cluster. Different vendors provide open-source device plugins for SGX:
Intel Azure Alibaba Cloud Marblerun checks if an SGX device plugin is already running and deploys Azure&amp;rsquo;s plugin otherwise. Note that the Azure SGX plugin is not tied to Azure.</description></item><item><title>Setting a Manifest</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/tasks/set-manifest/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 16:28:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/tasks/set-manifest/</guid><description>Setting a Manifest The Manifest is a JSON document that defines which services span the mesh and how they should be configured. It further defines what Infrastructure providers are allowed. You can set a Manifest through Marblerun&amp;rsquo;s Client REST-API. The endpoint for all Manifest operations is /manifest.
See the following Manifest for example (manifest.json).
{ &amp;#34;Packages&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;backend&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;UniqueID&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;6b2822ac2585040d4b9397675d54977a71ef292ab5b3c0a6acceca26074ae585&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ProductID&amp;#34;: 43, &amp;#34;SecurityVersion&amp;#34;: 1, &amp;#34;Debug&amp;#34;: false }, &amp;#34;frontend&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;SignerID&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;43361affedeb75affee9baec7e054a5e14883213e5a121b67d74a0e12e9d2b7a&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ProductID&amp;#34;: 42, &amp;#34;SecurityVersion&amp;#34;: 3, &amp;#34;Debug&amp;#34;: true } }, &amp;#34;Marbles&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;backend_first&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;Package&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;backend&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;MaxActivations&amp;#34;: 1, &amp;#34;Parameters&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;Files&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;/tmp/defg.</description></item><item><title>Monitoring and logging</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/tasks/monitoring/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 16:28:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/tasks/monitoring/</guid><description>Monitoring and logging As of now, the monitoring capabilities of Marblerun are basic. For status information, the Coordinator provides the /status endpoint in the client API. It returns the following information.
0 recovery mode: Found a sealed state of an old seal key. Waiting for user input on /recover. 1 uninitialized: Fresh start, initializing the Coordinator. 2 waiting for a manifest: Waiting for user input on /manifest 3 accepting marbles: Accepting Marbles through the Marble API More details about the Coordinator can be retrieved through its log as follows.</description></item><item><title>Verifying a deployment</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/tasks/verification/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 16:28:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/tasks/verification/</guid><description>Verifying a deployment An important feature of Marblerun is providing the ability to verifying the confidentiality and integrity of the whole application on the client-side. To that end, we provide a simple REST-API that clients can use before interacting with the application.
Establishing trust The first step is to establish trust with the whole microservice mesh. Therefore, Marblerun exposes the /quote endpoint that returns a quote and a certificate chain consisting of a root CA and an intermediate CA for the whole mesh.</description></item><item><title>Changelog</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/changelog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 16:28:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/changelog/</guid><description>Changelog Version 0.3.0 Add support for privileged Client API endpoints Allow increasing the minimum required SecurityVersion for packages after a manifest has been set initially (also referred to as &amp;lsquo;Manifest Update&amp;rsquo;) Add an intermediate certificate to the Marblerun certificate chain. Keep the root certificate permanent and change the intermediate with each manifest update. Return the whole cert-chain on the client API. Clients can pin the intermediate for automatically catching a manifest update.</description></item><item><title>Updating a deployment</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/tasks/updates/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 16:28:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/tasks/updates/</guid><description>Updating a deployment The following gives a walkthrough of typical deployment updates in a Kubernetes cluster and how to handle them with Marblerun.
Updating to a new Marblerun version When updating to a new Marblerun version, updates to both the control plane and data plane components may be required.
Updating the Coordinator Updating the Coordinator follows the regular steps for updating a deployment in Kubernetes.
kubectl -n marblerun set image deployment/marblerun-coordinator coordinator=ghcr.</description></item><item><title>Recovering the Coordinator</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/tasks/recover-coordinator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 15:53:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/tasks/recover-coordinator/</guid><description>Recovering the Coordinator As described in our recovery chapter, different situations can require the recovery of the Coordinator. If the Coordinator finds a sealed state during its startup which it is unable to unseal using the host-specific SGX sealing key, it will wait for further instructions. You have two options:
Recover the sealed state by uploading the recovery secret, which was encrypted for the RecoveryKeys defined in the Manifest</description></item><item><title>Marblerun - Community</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/community/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 16:28:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/community/</guid><description> Community Marblerun is a community project and very much open to contributions. Let's work together and build the fabric for confidential cloud-native applications! &amp;nbsp;Get involved &amp;nbsp;Report a bug &amp;nbsp;GitHub &amp;nbsp;Get support &amp;nbsp;Join us on Gitter &amp;nbsp;Send a mail &amp;nbsp;Get updates &amp;nbsp;Twitter</description></item></channel></rss>