<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Deployment on Marblerun - The Control Plane for Confidential Computing</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/deployment/</link><description>Recent content in Deployment on Marblerun - The Control Plane for Confidential Computing</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://marblerun.sh/docs/deployment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cloud</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/deployment/cloud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/deployment/cloud/</guid><description>Cloud deployment This guide walks you through setting up Marblerun on different CSP offerings individually.
Azure confidential computing VMs Azure confidential computing services are generally available and provide access to VMs with Intel SGX enabled in DCsv2 VM instances. The description below uses a VM running Ubuntu 18.04.
Prerequisites Update and install EGo Update and install the Azure DCAP client Deploy Marblerun You can run Marblerun standalone on your Azure DCsv2 VM, see our standalone guide.</description></item><item><title>On-premises</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/deployment/on-prem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/deployment/on-prem/</guid><description>On-premises Marblerun deployment This guide walks you through setting up Marblerun for your on-premises deployment.
Prerequisites Hardware and firmware CPU To deploy Marblerun with Intel SGX, the machine or VM has to support Intel SGX. Particularly, Marblerun requires support for the SGX Datacenter Attestation Primitives (DCAP). You can verify if your CPU supports DCAP.
For more information read the Properly Detecting Intel Software Guard Extensions (Intel® SGX) in Your Applications article.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/deployment/kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/deployment/kubernetes/</guid><description>Kubernetes Marblerun deployment This guide walks you through setting up Marblerun in your Kubernetes cluster.
Prerequisites SGX device plugin on Kubernetes Kubernetes manages hardware resources like Intel SGX through its device plugin framework. The SGX device plugin can either be deployed manually or as a DaemonSet in the cluster. Different vendors provide open-source device plugins for SGX:
Intel Azure Alibaba Cloud &amp;nbsp;Note If you are using a CC-enlightened, managed Kubernetes cluster, you will usually already have an SGX device plugin installed.</description></item><item><title>Standalone</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/deployment/standalone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/deployment/standalone/</guid><description>Standalone Marblerun deployment This guide walks you through deploying Marblerun standalone.
Prerequisites EGo is installed. Setup the Coordinator control plane You can download the latest release of our Coordinator control plane on GitHub. If you prefer to build from source please refer to our build guide.
You can then run the Coordinator&amp;rsquo;s enclave:
erthost build/coordinator-enclave.signed Per default, the Coordinator starts with the following default values. You can set your desired configuration by setting the environment variables.</description></item></channel></rss>