<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docs on Marblerun - The Control Plane for Confidential Computing</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Docs on Marblerun - The Control Plane for Confidential Computing</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 16:28:16 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marblerun.sh/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 16:28:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/introduction/</guid><description>Introduction Marblerun is a framework for creating distributed confidential-computing apps.
Build your confidential microservices with EGo or another runtime, distribute them with Kubernetes on an SGX-enabled cluster, and let Marblerun take care of the rest. Deploy end-to-end secure and verifiable AI pipelines or crunch on sensitive big data in the cloud. Confidential computing at scale has never been easier.
Marblerun guarantees that the topology of your distributed app adheres to a Manifest specified in simple JSON.</description></item><item><title>Changelog</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/changelog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 16:28:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/changelog/</guid><description>Changelog Version 0.3.2 CLI: Add auto-complete support Add sgxsdk-package-info: Prints the package signature properties of an SGX SDK binary Kubernetes SGX-device-plugin refactoring: Don&amp;rsquo;t install own device-plugin with Marblerun Auto-detect installed device-plugin Add support for Intel&amp;rsquo;s device-plugin Marbles: EGo: Let EGo handle filesystem mounts Occlum: Add support for Occlum workloads Graphene: Use execve instead of posix_spawn due to performance Remove obsolete preload option for premain Cleanup and improve BUILD.</description></item></channel></rss>