<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reference on Marblerun - The Control Plane for Confidential Computing</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/reference/</link><description>Recent content in Reference on Marblerun - The Control Plane for Confidential Computing</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 16:28:16 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marblerun.sh/docs/reference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Coordinator API</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/reference/coordinator/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 16:28:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/reference/coordinator/</guid><description>Coordinator client API JSend response style Endpoints /manifest /quote /recover /secrets /status /update JSend response style The Client API is designed as an HTTP-REST interface. Responses follow the JSend style, though only the response types success and error are returned so far.
In general, a successful API call (HTTP Code 200) will return a response in the following style:
{ &amp;#34;status&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;success&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;data&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;ManifestSignature&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;3fff78e99dd9bd801e0a3a22b7f7a24a492302c4d00546d18c7f7ed6e26e95c3&amp;#34; } } Depending on the API endpoint and the data submitted, data might contain a specific answer from the Coordinator, or may just be null to acknowledge that the requested operation was performed successfully.</description></item><item><title>CLI</title><link>https://marblerun.sh/docs/reference/cli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marblerun.sh/docs/reference/cli/</guid><description>Command Line Interface (CLI) We provide a command-line interface (CLI) for Marblerun. This CLI allows you to install Marblerun on your cluster and interacts with the control plane through the Client API for all administrative tasks in the service mesh.
Installation Requirements Command certificate root intermediate chain Command check Command completion Command graphene-prepare Command install Command manifest set update get log signature verify Command namespace add remove list Command precheck Command recover Command secret get set Command status Command uninstall Command version Installation To install the Marblerun CLI on your machine you can use our pre-built binaries.</description></item></channel></rss>